Finding Aid for the Oliver Cromwell Carmichael Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Activities and organizations - Boards
  - Affiliations – other organizations and institutions
    - Council of Graduate Schools in the United States-OCC representing Ford Foundation (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Council on Student Travel (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - Danforth Foundation,-Annual Reports, 1961-1963 (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - Danforth Foundation-Workshop, 1962 (Box 94, Folder 11)
    - Danforth Foundation – Questionnaire, 1962 (Box 94, Folder 12)
    - Danforth Foundation - Workshop, 1963 (Box 94, Folder 13)
    - Danforth Foundation – Workshop, 1963 (Box 94, Folder 14)
    - Danforth Foundation – Workshop, 1963 (Box 94, Folder 15)
    - Danforth Foundation – Workshop, 1963 (Box 94, Folder 16)
  - Affiliations – other organizations and institutions
    - David Davies Memorial Institute of International Studies – London, 1962 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Downtown Club (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - East Carolina College – Closed Circuit Television Experiment; other (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Educational and Cultural Advancement in Latin America – Report (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Educational Policies Commission – Meeting, May 1947 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Educational Services Incorporated (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - Educational Television (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Educational Testing Service – Princeton, New Jersey (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Elizabeth City State Teachers College – North Carolina (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - English Speaking Union – Asheville, N.C. (Box 95, Folder 10)
    - Erskine College – South Carolina (Box 95, Folder 11)
    - Fisk University – Nashville, TN (Box 95, Folder 12)
    - Florida State Chamber of Commerce (Box 95, Folder 13)
    - Ford Foundation – comments by OCC (Box 95, Folder 14)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 95, Folder 15)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 95, Folder 16)
    - Ford Foundation – Teacher Education Reports (Box 95, Folder 17)
    - Ford Foundation – Teacher Education Reports (Box 95, Folder 18)
    - Ford Foundation – Teacher Education Reports (Box 95, Folder 19)
    - Ford Foundation – Teacher Education Reports (Box 95, Folder 20)
    - Ford Foundation – Dr. Alvin Eurich C. (Box 95, Folder 21)
  - Affiliations – other organizations and institutions
    - Ford Foundation – Correspondence, publications, other (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Ford Foundation - Report (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Ford Foundation – Brief on University of Ottawa (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Foreign Aspects of National Security – Conference materials (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Foreign Aspects of National Security – Conference materials (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Fund for the Advancement of Education – Aspen conference (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Gonser and Gerber/Public Relations and Development (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Graduate Education – North Carolina (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - Graduate Education Programs – Carnegie Conference on Higher Education, 1957 (Box 96, Folder 9)
    - Graduate Education Programs – Harvard Studies in Career Development, No.8, 1958 (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - Graduate Education Programs – general (Box 96, Folder 11)
    - Graduate Schools Programs – University of Oregon, March 1959 (Box 96, Folder 12)
    - Graduate Schools Programs – University of Washington, 1958-1959 (Box 96, Folder 13)
    - Graduate Schools Programs in the U.S. (Box 96, Folder 14)
    - Graduate Studies Programs – University of Colorado, 1959 (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - Affiliations – other organizations and institutions
    - Great Lakes Colleges Association, 1962-1964 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Harvard University – Aspen Conference Report, October 1959 (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Harvard University – Report of the Seminar, 1960 (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - Health Research Foundation (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Herbert Hoover Memorial (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - Institute for Advanced Study – Princeton, N.J. (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Industry – Education Conference on Manpower Resources in the South, 1960 (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - International Association of Universities, 1958 (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - International Institute for Study and Research in the field of Commercial Competition (Box 97, Folder 9)
    - International Movement for Atlantic Union (Box 97, Folder 10)
    - Iowa Tests of Educational Development, 1957 (Box 97, Folder 11)
    - Jacksonville University – Founder’s Day Award to OCC, 1965 (Box 97, Folder 12)
    - Jefferson National Expansion Memorial Association – OCC Board of Trustees (Box 97, Folder 13)
    - Juvenile Planning Council of Asheville, N.C., 1954–1960 (Box 97, Folder 14)
    - Kansas institutions – reports and correspondence (Box 97, Folder 15)
    - Kansas institutions – reports and correspondence (Box 97, Folder 16)
    - Kansas institutions – newspaper articles (Box 97, Folder 17)
    - Kenyon College (Box 97, Folder 18)
    - Lake Logan Medical Conference – report and address by William C. Menninger, May 1959 (Box 97, Folder 19)
    - Leaders of Institutes of World Affairs (Box 97, Folder 20)
    - Lincoln Sesquicentennial Commission (Box 97, Folder 21)
    - Los Angeles City Schools (Box 97, Folder 22)
  - Affiliations – other organizations and institutions
    - Markle Foundation (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Markle Scholars in Academic Medicine (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Mars Hill College (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Mercer University – Report on Negro Admissions, April 1963 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Mercy College, Detroit, Michigan (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Ministry of Education – London, 1956 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Montreat – Anderson College (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - Montreat – Anderson College (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - Montreat – Anderson College (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - Montreat – Anderson College (Box 98, Folder 10)
    - National Commission on Accrediting (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - National Commission on Accrediting (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - National Conference on Regional Education (Box 98, Folder 13)
    - National Council for Prevention of War, 1933 (Box 98, Folder 14)
    - National Education Association (Box 98, Folder 15)
    - National Education Association (Box 98, Folder 16)
    - National Foundation for Educational Research in England and Wales (Box 98, Folder 17)
    - National Institutes for Health – Charles V. Kidd (Box 98, Folder 18)
    - National Social Welfare Assembly, report 1955 (Box 98, Folder 19)
    - Newcomen Society in North America (Box 98, Folder 20)
    - New College – Sarasota, Florida (Box 98, Folder 21)
    - New England Board of Higher Education (Box 98, Folder 22)
  - Affiliatons – other organizations and institutions
    - New York University (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - New Zealand Institute of Economic Research (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - New Zealand Institute of Economic Research (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - North Carolina related materials (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - North Carolina Advisory Committee (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - North Carolina Defender of States Rights (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - North Carolina State College (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - North Central Association (Box 99, Folder 8)
    - Ohio Study – reports from universities (Box 99, Folder 9)
    - Ohio Study – reports from universities (Box 99, Folder 10)
    - Ohio Study – “Provisional Master Plan for Public Higher Education in Ohio”, April 1965 (Box 99, Folder 11)
    - Pennsylvania State University – Demonstration proposal, 1965 (Box 99, Folder 12)
    - Pennsylvania Study (Box 99, Folder 13)
    - Pharmaceutical Manufacturers – Statement of Thomas Carney, February 1960 (Box 99, Folder 14)
    - Project to Combat International Communism, May 1954 (Box 99, Folder 15)
    - Randolph- Macon Woman’s College, April 1941 (Box 99, Folder 16)
    - Research Corporation – Proposal, 1962 (Box 99, Folder 17)
    - “The Round Table”, Fall 1945 (Box 99, Folder 18)
    - St. Olaf’s College (Box 99, Folder 19)
    - Robert and Rose Skillman Memorial Foundation, October 1962 (Box 99, Folder 20)
    - Southern Fellowship Fund (Box 99, Folder 21)
  - Affiliations – other organizations and institutions
    - Southern Historical Association – papers on segregation decisions, 1955 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Southern Humanities Conference (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Stanford Secondary Education Project, October 1959 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Stillman College – Samuel B. Hay (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Television – Midwest Airborne Communiques (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Theodore Roosevelt Centennial Commission (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - 3M/Age Company (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - Tufts University (Box 100, Folder 8)
    - Tufts University (Box 100, Folder 9)
    - Tulane University (Box 100, Folder 10)
    - United Kingdom – Education publications (Box 100, Folder 11)
    - U.S. Department of Commerce (Box 100, Folder 12)
    - U.S. Educational Foundation – Austria, 1956-1958 (Box 100, Folder 13)
    - U.S. Educational Foundation – Belgium/Luxembourg, 1956-1958 (Box 100, Folder 14)
    - U.S. Educational Foundation – Greece, 1956-1958 (Box 100, Folder 15)
    - U.S. Educational Foundation – India, 1956-1958 (Box 100, Folder 16)
    - U.S. Educational Foundation – Pakistan, 1956-1958 (Box 100, Folder 17)
    - University Center in Virginia – (Fund for the Advancement of Education/Alvin Eurich (Box 100, Folder 18)
    - University of Alabama Medical Center, 1949–1964 (Box 100, Folder 19)
    - University of Leeds – Institute of Education – 1948-1950;Joint Matriculation Board (Box 100, Folder 20)
    - University of Michigan, 1962 (Box 100, Folder 21)
  - Affiliations – other organizations and institutions
    - University of Michigan, 1963 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - University of New Hampshire – Programs for Lecture Series, 1957-1958 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - University of North Carolina (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - University of Puerto Rico (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - University of Texas at Austin, 1954 (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - University of Texas at Austin – Conference materials, 1958 (Box 101, Folder 7)
    - University of Texas at Austin – Conference materials, 1958 (Box 101, Folder 8)
    - University of Tomorrow (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - University of Tomorrow (Box 101, Folder 10)
    - University of Tomorrow (Box 101, Folder 11)
    - University of Tomorrow (Box 101, Folder 12)
    - University of Tomorrow (Box 101, Folder 13)
    - University of Tomorrow (Box 101, Folder 14)
  - Affiliations – other organizations and institutions
    - University of Tomorrow (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Wake Forest College, North Carolina – Board of Visitors (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Wake Forest College, North Carolina – 1962 Reports of Consultants in Study of Graduate Programs (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Wake Forest College, North Carolina – 1962 Reports of Consultants in Study of Graduate Programs (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Wake Forest College, North Carolina – 1962 Reports of Consultants in Study of Graduate Programs (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Wake Forest College, North Carolina – 1962 Reports of Consultants in Study of Graduate Programs (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Wake Forest College, North Carolina – 1962 Reports of Consultants in Study of Graduate Programs (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Wake Forest College, North Carolina – Carmichael – McCutcheon Report, 1963 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - West Virginia University- Department of History Newsletter, 1964-65 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Western Carolina College, North Carolina – “Gifted Children”, 1958 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Western Association of Graduate Schools, March 30-31, 1959 (Box 102, Folder 11)
    - Westinghouse Educational Foundation (Box 102, Folder 12)
    - Westminster Schools, Atlanta, Georgia – Report (Box 102, Folder 13)
    - Wildcat Veterans Association (Box 102, Folder 14)
    - Wilmington College, 1960 (Box 102, Folder 15)
    - Woman’s College of the University of North Carolina, Greensboro (Box 102, Folder 16)
    - Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation (Box 102, Folder 17)
    - Yale University Catalog, 1841-1851 (Box 102, Folder 18)
    - Yeshiva University, 1959 (Box 102, Folder 19)
    - Youth Leadership Programs (Box 102, Folder 20)
  - Research Index cards
    - Africa (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Australia (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Canada (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Commonwealth (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - India (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - New Zealand (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Pakistan (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - United Kingdom (Box 103, Folder 8)
    - U.S.A. (Box 103, Folder 9)
- Oversize -Memorabilia
  - Items relating to OCC’s inauguration as the Chancellor of Vanderbilt University, February 5, 1938
    - University of South Carolina (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Indiana University (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - University of California (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - Louisiana State University (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - University of Florida (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - The Ohio State University (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - Wesleyan University (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - Dartmouth College (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - State Teachers College of Farmsville, Virginia (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - Alabama College (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - Agnes Scott; Austin College;Emory University; The George Washington University; Goucher College; Harvard College; Hobart College; Princeton University (Box 104, Folder 12)
    - Universidad de Buenos Aires; University of Chicago; Universite de Lyon; University of Pennsylvania; University of Tennessee; Vassar College (Box 104, Folder 13)
    - Other – University of Alabama (Box 104, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous papers
  - (Box 105)